In the last lesson we talked about how to describe your routine how to talk about what you do.
在上一课中，我们讨论了如何描述你的日常工作如何谈论你所做的事情。
Usually on a normal day and also how to talk about your responsibilities.
通常在正常的一天，以及如何谈论你的责任。
In this lesson we're going to be talking about how to start a conversation.
在本课中，我们将讨论如何开始对话。
You're probably taking this course because you want to learn how to have conversations with other people.
您可能正在学习这门课程，因为您想学习如何与其他人进行对话。
Maybe native English speakers in work situations or maybe in your daily life.
也许在工作场合或日常生活中以英语为母语的人。
So this class will focus on how we begin those conversations naturally.
因此，本课程将重点关注我们如何自然地开始这些对话。
It's actually not as hard as you may think.
它实际上并不像你想象的那么难。
Once you get started in a conversation it's pretty easy to keep it going but getting started in a conversation
一旦开始对话，就很容易继续进行，但开始对话
can be difficult.
可能很困难。
If you don't know what you're doing or how to do it.
如果你不知道自己在做什么或如何去做。
So that's what this class is all about.
这就是这门课的全部内容。
We're going to talk about some techniques for doing it and then as we always do we're going to look
我们将讨论一些实现它的技术，然后像往常一样，我们将看看
at a couple of real life examples so that you can deeply get the feeling for it so that when you go
在几个现实生活中的例子，这样你就可以深刻地感受到它，这样当你去的时候
out there to have conversations it'll be easy.
在那里进行对话会很容易。
Tip number one for having conversations is whenever you find yourself in a situation with other people
进行对话的第一个提示是每当您发现自己与其他人处于某种情况时
and you'd like to start a conversation you first have to realize what situation you're in.
你想开始一段对话，你首先必须了解你所处的情况。
You may have learned that talking about the weather is always a good way to begin talking with somebody
您可能已经了解到，谈论天气始终是开始与某人交谈的好方法
right.
正确的。
It's pretty hot these days isn't it.
这几天很热对不对。
This is the traditional way that many English language learners are taught to begin conversations.
这是许多英语学习者被教导开始对话的传统方式。
Oh it's it's pretty hot today but this is a little bit awkward and doesn't work in every situation.
哦，今天很热，但这有点尴尬，并不是在所有情况下都有效。
How about this weather.
这个天气怎么样。
These are sort of the traditional things what you can do instead is pay careful attention to what the
这些是一些传统的事情，你可以做的是仔细注意
situation is and when you do that you will see what you share with the other person the person you want
情况是，当你这样做时，你会看到你与其他人分享你想要的人
to talk with and when you realize what you share with that person you'll be able to pick out a good
交谈，当你意识到你与那个人分享了什么，你就可以挑选出一个好的
question that is natural that can make that person want to say something or pick out a good comment
很自然的问题，可以让那个人想说点什么或挑出一个好的评论
to say to the other person that will make them want to talk with you right.
对另一个人说，这会让他们想和你说话。
So focus on where you are.
所以专注于你在哪里。
Are you at a doctor's office.
你在医生办公室吗？
Are you in the park.
你在公园里吗？
Are you in a class.
你在上课吗。
Are you in your workplace.
你在你的工作场所吗？
What things do you have in common with that person.
你和那个人有什么共同点。
Then how can you make a comment or a question based on that.
那么您如何基于此发表评论或问题。
Now sometimes the thing that you have in common is not the whole situation itself but something the
现在，有时你们的共同点不是整个情况本身，而是某种
other person is doing or wearing right.
其他人正在做或穿着正确。
For example if you like skateboarding and you see another person skateboarding obviously that's the
例如，如果你喜欢滑板，而你看到另一个人在滑板，那显然是
thing that you should use to begin a conversation but it could also be what somebody is wearing maybe
你应该用来开始对话的东西，但它也可能是某人穿着的东西
a watch and you know something about watches and you can use that.
一块手表，你知道一些关于手表的知识，你可以使用它。
We'll look at examples of how to do that later on.
稍后我们将查看如何执行此操作的示例。
So these are the two questions I ask myself before I start a conversation with somebody and I'm thinking
所以这是我在开始与某人交谈之前问自己的两个问题，我在想
about how to begin what to say right.
关于如何开始说什么正确。
That first difficult thing whether it's a comment or question what situation are we in.
第一件困难的事情，无论是评论还是质疑我们所处的情况。
What do we have in common whatever you come up with then after you ask yourself these questions can
无论你想出什么，我们有什么共同点，然后在你问自己这些问题之后
then be the basic idea that you use to make a comment or ask a question to the person you want to start
然后成为您用来向您想要开始的人发表评论或提问的基本想法
a conversation with.
与。
If you ask a question that comes out of nowhere and it's just a shot in the dark do you like basketball
如果你问一个不知从何而来的问题，而这只是在黑暗中投篮，你喜欢篮球吗？
then it's likely probable that the person you asked that question too will feel uncomfortable awkward
那么你问那个曲的人很可能esttion也会觉得不舒服别扭
awkward but if it is really an interesting question that focuses on what is shared between you then
尴尬，但如果这真的是一个有趣的问题，专注于你们之间共享的内容，那么
that person will feel interested in what you asked and will want to talk.
那个人会对你的问题感兴趣并想谈一谈。
Make it your goal to say something that makes the other person want to say something back.
把说一些让对方想要回嘴的话作为你的目标。
If you're doing all the hard work then it's not really a conversation.
如果您正在做所有艰苦的工作，那么这并不是真正的对话。
So for example a lot of people send me messages on on WeChat right.
例如，很多人在微信上给我发信息。
I'm always on on WeChat which has a it's like Facebook messenger if you don't know it.
我总是在微信上，如果你不知道的话，它就像 Facebook Messenger。
And they often say for example or how long have you been using WeChat.
他们经常说，例如，你使用微信多久了。
Well that's it.
就是这样。
That's a pretty good question because that's the first time they've connected with me on WeChat and
这是一个很好的问题，因为这是他们第一次在微信上与我联系
it's something we both have in common.
这是我们俩的共同点。
Hey we both use WeChat so it's an interesting question.
嘿，我们都使用微信，所以这是一个有趣的问题。
It makes me want to answer it.
这让我想回答它。
So maybe if somebody has seen one of my other courses or video and messages me we can use the fact that
因此，也许如果有人看过我的其他课程或视频并给我发信息，我们可以使用以下事实
we don't know each other to ask interesting questions like.
我们不认识对方问一些有趣的问题。
Which city do you live in.
你生活在哪个城市。
And then we can ask more questions about that.
然后我们可以就此提出更多问题。
The thing we have in common is that we don't know physically where the other person is because maybe
我们的共同点是我们不知道对方在哪里，因为也许
we're contacting on WeChat sometimes email because we don't know that that can be the thing that we
我们在微信上联系有时会发电子邮件，因为我们不知道那可能是我们的事情
share.
分享。
So that can be the interesting question.
所以这可能是一个有趣的问题。
Which city do you live in.
你生活在哪个城市。
Which country do you live in.
你住在哪个国家。
Where are you from.
你从哪来。
And we use the same basic idea to make comments.
我们使用相同的基本思想来发表评论。
Again if somebody's messages me who I've never talked to before maybe because they saw a video or maybe
再说一次，如果有人给我发消息，而我以前从未与之交谈过，可能是因为他们看了视频，或者可能
saw one of my courses they might say for example you've probably seen so many different kinds of incorrect
看过我的一门课程，他们可能会说，例如，你可能见过很多不同类型的错误
English which is absolutely right.
英语是绝对正确的。
And then I'll say yes absolutely and then maybe I'll want to share a funny story that one is not based
然后我肯定会说是的，然后也许我会想分享一个有趣的故事
on where we are it's based on something that we share which is that maybe I've taught languages and
关于我们在哪里，它基于我们分享的一些东西，也许我教过语言和
your learning languages.
你的学习语言。
So messaging me using that thing that we share and making a comment about what may be true about my
所以用我们分享的东西给我发消息，并对我的真实情况发表评论
life and about me even if it's wrong is a good start because if it's not right at least I can correct
生活和关于我，即使它是错误的，也是一个好的开始，因为如果它不正确，至少我可以纠正
you.
你。
And that can be that could be an interesting beginning point as well.
这也可能是一个有趣的起点。
When you're starting a conversation it's very important to judge body language.
当你开始谈话时，判断肢体语言非常重要。
There are times when you're going to maybe start a conversation and the other person doesn't want to
有时您可能会开始对话而对方不想
talk to you.
对你说。
You need to be able to notice that and let it go and accept that maybe this time it's not working okay.
您需要能够注意到这一点并放手并接受这一次它可能无法正常工作。
And it's the same if somebody is trying to talk with you and you're not in the mood or you're thinking
如果有人试图与您交谈而您没有心情或者您正在思考，情况也是如此
about something else or you're busy on your phone you'll show that with your body language what you
关于别的事情，或者你正忙着打电话，你会用你的肢体语言来表达你的意思
do with your body what you do with your face your facial expression maybe.
用你的身体做你的脸，你的面部表情。
So if people show impatience or if they seem like they're maybe a bit distracted or if they give very
因此，如果人们表现出不耐烦，或者他们看起来可能有点分心，或者如果他们付出非常
short answers it's probably best to move on and maybe talk to somebody else because they're probably
简短的答案可能最好继续前进，也许与其他人交谈，因为他们可能
trying to show you or signal hey not really in the mood for a conversation now or I just I don't really
试图向你展示或示意嘿，现在并没有真正的谈话心情，或者我只是我真的没有
want want to talk.
想说话。
It's not always rude right.
这并不总是对的。
But sometimes people just don't really want to have a conversation and that's OK so you have to be able
但有时人们只是不想进行对话，这没关系，所以你必须能够
to pay attention to people's reactions to their faces and see if they're interested genuinely in talking
关注人们对他们面部的反应，看看他们是否真的有兴趣交谈
with you or not.
和你在一起与否。
If not don't try to force it.
如果不是，不要试图强迫它。
Not a good idea.
不是一个好主意。